Guide to the Eugene O'Neill Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Photographs, 1889-1968; Series V; 7.6; (20 boxes)
  - PLAY PRODUCTIONS
    - Cycle plays
      - A Touch of the Poet
        - Theater am Kurfürstendamm in Berlin (Germany). Fourteen shots by Heinz Köster, 1958 Apr 15 (Box 118, Folder 2233)
        - Theater am Kurfürstendamm in Berlin (Germany). One shot by Ruth Wilhelmi, [1958 Apr 15] (Box 118, Folder 2234)
        - Salzburg (Austria). Three shots by F. Schreiber, n.d. (Box 118, Folder 2235)
        - Finnish National Theatre in Helsinki (Finland). Five shots by Lehtikuva Oy (Box 118, Folder 2236)
        - Düsseldorf (Germany). One shot by Lore Bermbach, n.d. (Box 118, Folder 2237)
        - Düsseldorf (Germany). Two shots by Hans-J. Witkowski, n.d. (Box 118, Folder 2238)
        - Düsseldorf (Germany). One shot by Jürgen Theis, n.d. (Box 118, Folder 2239)
        - Hamburg (Germany). Four shots by Rosemarie Clausen, n.d. (Box 118, Folder 2240)
        - Amsterdam (Netherlands). Two shots by Lemaire en wennink (Box 118, Folder 2241)
        - The Producers Theatre (New York, N.Y.). Twenty-nine shots by Fred Fehl, n.d. (Box 118, Folder 2242-2246)
        - The Producers Theatre (New York, N.Y.). Sixteen shots by Alfredo Valente, n.d. (Box 118, Folder 2247-2248)
        - Stockholm (Sweden). Twenty-nine shots by Beata Bergström, n.d. (Box 118, Folder 2249-2251)
    - Days Without End
      - Theatre Guild at Henry Miller Theatre (New York, N.Y.). Twelve shots by Vandamm Studio (New York, N.Y.), [1934] (Box 119, Folder 2252-2253)
        folder 2633
      - Dramatiska teatern (Stockholm, Sweden). Three shots by Almberg & Preinitz, 1935 Apr 23 (Box 119, Folder 2254)
      - [Berlin (Germany)?]. One shot, [1938?] (Box 119, Folder 2255)
    - Desire Under the Elms
      - [Dramatiska teatern (Stockholm, Sweden)?]. One shot, [192-?]
      - Gate Theatre (London, England). Seventeen shots on two posters, 1931 Feb 24
      - Dramatiska teatern (Stockholm, Sweden). Six shots by Almberg & Preinitz, 1933 Oct 19 (Box 119, Folder 2256)
      - Westminster Theatre (London, England). Sixteen shots by Houston Rogers, [1940] (Box 119, Folder 2257-2258)
      - Bucharest (Romania). Four shots, 1964-65 (Box 119, Folder 2259)
      - Toneeloroep Theater (Amsterdam, Netherlands). Two shots by Maria Austria, [1965] (Box 119, Folder 2260)
      - Turkish Workers Theatre (Baku, Azerbaijan). One shot, n.d. (Box 119, Folder 2261)
        On back: one note from [J. D. P.?] to
        EO; one note from Frank Shay to
        Barrett Harper Clark.
      - Prague (Czech Republic). Two shots by Karel Vána, n.d. (Box 119, Folder 2262)
      - Kamerny Theatre (Moscow, Russia). Three shots, n.d. (Box 119, Folder 2263)
      - Unidentified production. Four shots, n.d. (Box 119, Folder 2264)
    - Dynamo
      - Theatre Guild at Martin Beck Theatre
        - Ten shots by Vandamm Studio (New York, N.Y.), 1929 [Feb 11] (Box 119, Folder 2265)
        - One shot by unidentified (2 prints), 1929 [Feb 11] (Box 119, Folder 2266)
          Both annotated on back in
          unidentified hand.
    - The Emperor Jones
      - Provincetown Players at The Playwrights' Theatre. Ten shots by Jessie Tarbox Beals, 1920 Nov 1 (Box 119, Folder 2267)
      - Puppet production. Nine shots by Helen Liebman, [192-]
      - Six photographs of six drawings by Walter René Fuerst, [192-?] (Box 119, Folder 2268)
      - Stockholm (Sweden). Five shots by Beata Bergström, [195-?] (Box 119, Folder 2269)
      - Hallucinations. Three shots by William Horace Smith, n.d. (Box 119, Folder 2270)
    - The Fountain
      - Greenwich Village Theatre (New York, N.Y.). Twenty-three shots, [1925 Dec 10] (Box 119, Folder 2271-2272)
    - The Great God Brown
      - Stockholm (Sweden). Five shots by Almberg & Preinitz, n.d. (Box 119, Folder 2273)
    - The Hairy Ape
      - Plymouth Theatre (New York, N.Y.)
        - Two contact sheets by Abbe Studio (New York, N.Y.), 1922 (Box 119, Folder 2274)
          CMO in some shots.
        - Ten shots by Abbe Studio (New York, N.Y.), 1922
      - Kamerny Theatre (Moscow, Russia). Four shots, n.d. (Box 119, Folder 2275)
    - Hughie
      - Dramatiska teatern (Stockholm, Sweden). Twelve shots by Beata Bergström, [1958 Sep 18] (Box 119, Folder 2276)
    - The Iceman Cometh
      - Dramatiska teatern (Stockholm, Sweden). Thirty-two shots by Sven Jarlas, 1947 Oct 31 (Box 120, Folder 2277-2280)
      - Dublin (Ireland). Eight shots by P. C., 1948 (Box 120, Folder 2281)
      - Genova (Italy). Sixteen shots by Pierluigi, 1965 Dec 21 (Box 120, Folder 2282-2283)
      - Copenhagen (Denmark). One shot by H. J. Mydtskov
      - Amsterdam (Netherlands). Two shots by Maria Austria (Box 120, Folder 2284)
    - Ile
      - Opera version by Kungliga teatern (Stockholm, Sweden). Two shots by Enar Merkel Rydberg, 1958 Oct 28 (Box 120, Folder 2285)
      - Lae (Papua, New Guinea). Ten shots, 1963 (Box 120, Folder 2286)
      - Japan, translated and directed by Kihachi Kitamura. Two shots
    - In the Zone
      - Provincetown Players. One shot, [1918] (Box 120, Folder 2287)
    - Lazarus Laughed
      - Pasadena (Calif.)
        - One shot by A. E. Arnold, [1928 Apr 9] (Box 120, Folder 2288)
        - Twenty-two shots by unidentified, 1928 Apr 9 (Box 120, Folder 2289-2290)
    - Long Day's Journey Into Night
      - Shubert Theater (New Haven, Conn.). Four publicity shots by Arthur Cantor, [1956] (Box 120, Folder 2291)
      - Berlin (Germany). Three shots by Heinz Köster, 1956 (Box 120, Folder 2292)
      - Helen Hayes Theatre (New York, N.Y.). Thirteen shots by Gjon Mili, [1956] (Box 120, Folder 2293-2294)
      - Folkteatern (Göteborg, Sweden). Eight shots, [1961] (Box 120, Folder 2295)
      - Eleven motion picture stills by Dennis Stock, [1962]
      - (Copenhagen, Denmark). Ten shots by H. J. Mydtskov (Box 120, Folder 2296)
      - London (England). Eleven shots by Angus McBean (Box 120, Folder 2297)
      - Düsseldorf (Germany). Two shots by Jürgen Theis, n.d. (Box 120, Folder 2298)
      - National Theatre of Greece. Twenty-five shots, n.d. (Box 121, Folder 2299-2301)
      - Dublin (Ireland)
        - Two shots by Leinster Studios, n.d. (Box 121, Folder 2302)
        - Four shots by Lensmen, n.d. (Box 121, Folder 2303)
      - Milan (Italy). Nineteen shots by Mario Coppini, n.d. (Box 121, Folder 2304)
      - Amsterdam (Netherlands). One shot by Maria Austria (Box 121, Folder 2305)
      - Stockholm (Sweden)
        - Thirty-seven shots by Beata Bergström, n.d. (Box 121, Folder 2306-2308)
        - One shot by unidentified, n.d. (Box 121, Folder 2309)
    - The Long Voyage Home
      - Provincetown Players. Two shots by Paul Thompson, 1917 [Nov 2] (Box 121, Folder 2310)
      - Motion picture
        - Twenty-two shots, [1940] (Box 121, Folder 2311-2312)
        - One publicity shot from Minnesota Theatre Company, 1966 (Box 121, Folder 2313)
      - Japan. Two shots, n.d.
    - Marco Millions
      - The Repertory Theater of Lincoln Center. Six shots, 1964 (Box 121, Folder 2314)
    - A Moon for the Misbegotten
      - Dramatiska teatern (Stockholm, Sweden). Eleven shots by Sven Jarlas, 1953 Apr 24 (Box 121, Folder 2315)
      - Genova (Italy)
        - One shot by Ciemmefoto, 1958 (Box 121, Folder 2316)
        - One shot by De Antonis, [1958]
        - One shot by Invernizzi, [1958]
        - One shot by Foto Leoni, [1958]
        - One shot by Scalfati-Pisoni, [1958]
        - One shot by unidentified, [1958]
        - Three shots by unidentified, [1958] (Box 121, Folder 2317)
      - Bucharest (Romania). Five shots, 1964-65 (Box 121, Folder 2318)
      - Copenhagen (Denmark). Three shots by H. J. Mydtskov (Box 121, Folder 2319)
        Stored also in: Oversize, box 146,
        folder 2590
      - [Berlin (Germany)]. One shot, n.d. (Box 121, Folder 2320)
      - Amsterdam (Netherlands). Three shots by Maria Austria (Box 121, Folder 2321)
      - Amsterdam (Netherlands). Two shots by Lemaire en wennink (Box 121, Folder 2322)
    - The Moon of the Caribbees
      - Provincetown Players. Three shots, 1918 Dec 20 (Box 121, Folder 2323)
      - Unidentified production. Two shots, n.d. (Box 121, Folder 2324)
    - Mourning Becomes Electra
      - Theatre Guild. Thirty-three shots by Vandamm Studio (New York, N.Y.), 1931 Oct 26 (Box 122, Folder 2325-2332)
        One shot inscribed to CMO and EO by
        Earle [S--?].
      - Dramatiska teatern (Stockholm, Sweden)
        - Five shots by Almberg & Preinitz, 1933 Mar 29 (Box 122, Folder 2333)
        - Four shots by unidentified, 1933 Mar 29 (Box 122, Folder 2334)
      - Westminster Theatre (London, England). Twenty shots by Angus McBean, 1937-38 (Box 122, Folder 2335-2336)
        With note, holograph, of explanation
        by EO.
      - Teatrul National Bucuresti. Three volumes of postcards, 1943-44 (Box 123, Folder 2337-2339)
        Inscribed by Petru Comarnescu to EO.
      - Photographs (some by Alexander Kahle) from motion picture by Dudley Nichols, with postmarked envelopes sent by Dudley Nichols to Eugene O'Neill
        - Eight, 1947 Mar 25 (Box 123, Folder 2340)
        - Eighteen, 1947 Apr 28 (Box 123, Folder 2341-2342)
          For cover letter, see: Series I,
          Dudley Nichols to Eugene O'Neill,
          box 3, folder 121
        - Twenty-three, 1947 Apr 30 (Box 123, Folder 2343-2344)
        - Twenty-five, 1947 May 2 (Box 123, Folder 2345-2346)
        - Twenty-two, 1947 May 3 (Box 124, Folder 2347-2348)
        - Twelve, 1947 May 5 (Box 124, Folder 2349)
        - Thirty-five, 1947 May 8 (Box 124, Folder 2350-2352)
        - Seventeen, 1947 May 9 (Box 124, Folder 2353-2354)
        - Eighteen, 1947 May 10 (Box 124, Folder 2355-2356)
        - Eight, 1947 May 12 (Box 124, Folder 2357)
        - Thirteen, 1947 May 13 (Box 124, Folder 2358)
        - Twenty-two, 1947 May 14 (Box 124, Folder 2359-2360)
        - Seven, 1947 May 15 (Box 124, Folder 2361)
        - Seventeen, 1947 May 17 (Box 124, Folder 2362-2363)
        - Twelve, 1947 May 19 (Box 125, Folder 2364)
        - Nine, 1947 May 20 (Box 125, Folder 2365)
        - Thirty-two, 1947 May 21 (Box 125, Folder 2366-2368)
        - Nine, 1947 May 22 (Box 125, Folder 2369)
        - Thirty-three, 1947 May 23 (Box 125, Folder 2370-2372)
        - Sixteen, 1947 May 24 (Box 125, Folder 2373-2374)
        - Twelve, 1947 May 26 (Box 125, Folder 2375)
        - Eight, 1947 May 27 (Box 125, Folder 2376)
        - Twenty-five, 1947 Jun 6 (Box 125, Folder 2377-2378)
        - Four, 1947 Jun 7 (Box 126, Folder 2379)
        - Fourteen, 1947 Jun 9 (Box 126, Folder 2380-2381)
        - Seven, 1947 Jun 10 (Box 126, Folder 2382)
        - Twenty-one, 1947 Jun 16 (Box 126, Folder 2383-2384)
        - Seventeen, 1947 Jun 18 (Box 126, Folder 2385-2386)
        - Seven, 1947 Jun 19 (Box 126, Folder 2387)
        - Thirteen, 1947 Jun 20 (Box 126, Folder 2388)
        - Five, 1947 Jun 23 (Box 126, Folder 2389)
        - Fifteen, 1947 Jun 23 (Box 126, Folder 2390-2391)
        - Eight, 1947 Jun 26 (Box 126, Folder 2392)
      - Fifty-fix photographs (some by Alexander Kahle) from motion picture by Dudley Nichols, [1947] (Box 126, Folder 2393-2399)
      - Thirty photographs (some by Alexander Kahle) from motion picture by Dudley Nichols, [1947] (Box 127, Folder 2400-2403)
      - Photographs of seventeen drawings by Albert M. Pyke of scenes in motion picture by Dudley Nichols, [1947]
      - Motion picture by RKO Radio Pictures, directed by Dudley Nichols. Three reels, 1947
      - Frankfurt am Main (Germany). Twenty-two shots by Willi Klar, [1947]
        United States. War Dept. Civil
        Affairs Division to Richard J. Madden
        Play Company, Inc., box 15, folder
        356
      - University of Delaware. Two shots, 1956 Dec (Box 127, Folder 2404)
        With one shot of Aeschylus's Agamemnon.
      - Prague (Czech Republic). Fourteen shots by Foto Centropress, n.d. (Box 127, Folder 2405)
      - Berlin (Germany). Five shots by Heinz Köster, n.d. (Box 127, Folder 2406)
      - Bremen (Germany). Ten shots by Studio Lohrisch-Achilles, n.d. (Box 127, Folder 2407)
      - Lisbon (Portugal)
        - Fifteen shots by Horácio Novaes, n.d.
        - Twelve shots by unidentified, n.d. (Box 127, Folder 2408)
    - S. S. Glencairn
      - [New York, N.Y.?]. One shot, [1924?] (Box 127, Folder 2409)
        Annotated on back in unidentified
        hand.
      - Minnesota Theatre Company at Tyrone Guthrie Theatre (Minneapolis, Minn.). Eight shots; one postcard, 1966 (Box 127, Folder 2410)
    - Strange Interlude
      - Dramatiska teatern (Stockholm, Sweden)
        - One shot by Almberg & Preinitz, 1928 Mar 11 (Box 127, Folder 2411)
        - One shot by unidentified, 1928 Mar 11
      - Actors Theatre (New York, N.Y.). Twelve shots by Friedman-Abeles, [1963] (Box 127, Folder 2412)
    - Thirst
      - Provincetown Players at The Wharf Theatre (Provincetown, Mass.). Two shots, 1916 [Aug?] (Box 127, Folder 2413)
        EO is in both shots. One annotated on
        back by EO.
    - A Touch of the Poet
      See: Cycle plays, box 118, folders 2231-2251
    - Unidentified play
      - Unidentified production. Three shots by Stage Photo Company (London, England)
    - Unidentified play
      - Unidentified production. One shot by Stage Photo Company (London, England)
- Memorabilia, 1918-1958; Series VI; 1.2; (4 boxes)
  Series VI, Memorabilia, is organized into three
  subseries: Office Material, Personal Effects, and Other.
  - OFFICE MATERIAL
    Organized into Book-Related Items, Stationery, and
    Writing Tools.
    - Book-Related Items
      - Bookends. Set of two marble (Box 128, Folder 2414)
      - Bookplate-related items, n.d. (Box 128, Folder 2415)
        Item A: Bookplates in Dempsey &
        Carroll box. Item B: Seal from
        bookplate.
    - Stationery
      - American Trust Company blotters, 1939 (Box 128, Folder 2416)
      - Carlton House (New York, N.Y.). Sign for doorknob, n.d. (Box 128, Folder 2417)
      - Casa Genotta (Sea Island, Ga.). Three sheets of unused stationery (two types) (Box 128, Folder 2418)
      - Château du Plessis
        - One sheet of unused stationery, n.d. (Box 128, Folder 2419)
        - Stationery (unused), in notepad, n.d.
      - Envelopes. Two different, blank (unused), n.d. (Box 128, Folder 2420)
      - Grand Oriental Hotel, Colombo, Ceylon. Six sheets of unused stationery (Box 128, Folder 2421)
      - Hotel Ritz (Madrid, Spain). Envelope annotated "Stamps", n.d. (Box 128, Folder 2422)
        In CMO's hand. Includes two Spanish
        stamps.
      - Notebooks
        - Small notebook (unused) annotated on cover: "Plaza Tues 13 Noon", n.d. (Box 128, Folder 2423)
        - Two notebooks (unused), from China, with blue covers, n.d. (Box 128, Folder 2424-2425)
        - Two notebooks (unused), from China, with red covers, n.d. (Box 128, Folder 2426-2427)
      - Postcards (unused)
        - British Museum, n.d. (Box 129, Folder 2428-2430)
        - Chicago (Ill.), n.d. (Box 129, Folder 2431)
        - Córdoba (Spain), n.d. (Box 129, Folder 2432)
        - France, n.d. (Box 129, Folder 2433-2436)
        - M. V. Highland Chieftain (Box 129, Folder 2437)
        - Málaga (Spain), n.d. (Box 129, Folder 2438)
        - Metropolitan Museum of Art (New York, N.Y.), n.d. (Box 129, Folder 2439-2442)
        - Museum of the City of New York, n.d. (Box 129, Folder 2443)
        - San Francisco (Calif.), n.d. (Box 129, Folder 2444)
        - Schloss Neuschwanstein (Germany), n.d. (Box 129, Folder 2445)
        - Virginia, n.d. (Box 129, Folder 2446)
      - Visiting cards, n.d. (Box 129, Folder 2447)
    - Writing Tools
      - Pen, pencils, erasers, sharpener, and monogram stamp (Box 129, Folder 2448)
      - Portfolio, of brown leather with inside lining and folder in silver-patterned green silk, [1928] (Box 129, Folder 2449)
      - Portfolio, of brown leather with inside lining and folder in silver-patterned mulberry silk, [1928] (Box 129, Folder 2450)
      - Envelope with lock, of brown leather with inside lining in green leather, [1928] (Box 129, Folder 2451)
  - PERSONAL EFFECTS
    - Carlotta Monterey O'Neill
      - Braid, with red ribbon, n.d. (Box 130, Folder 2452)
        Donald Clifford Gallup.
      - Locks of hair, 1934 Jul, n.d. (Box 130, Folder 2453)
        Lighter-colored lock in envelope
        dated 1934 Jul; darker-colored lock
        undated.
    - Eugene O'Neill
      - "Gene's 'treasures'", 1918-34, n.d. (Box 130, Folder 2454-2455)
        Envelope with inscription in CMO's
        hand. Includes two bicycle racing
        programs; three brochures regarding
        cars; three brochures about Georgia
        and one leather armband.
      - Gold and crystal Cartier pocket watch on gold chain, engraved on back in capital letters: "To Gene from Carlotta, July 22 1930", 1930 Jul 22 (Box 130, Folder 2456)
        In red Cartier box.
      - Luggage tag for S. S. Coblenz, in Carlotta Monterey O'Neill's hand, 1928 Dec 11 (Box 130, Folder 2457)
      - Money won in crap game on S. S. Coblenz, 1928 (Box 130, Folder 2458)
        Various currencies, paper and coin.
      - Monograms from clothing, n.d. (Box 130, Folder 2459)
        Item A: plaid shirt pocket
        monogrammed "EO'N"; Item B: light
        green fabric fragment monogrammed
        "Gene."
      - Three keys, n.d. (Box 130, Folder 2460)
        Includes label in CMO's hand: "Eugene
        O'Neill."
    - Carlotta Monterey O'Neill and Eugene O'Neill
      - Black case from Guaranty Trust Company of New York, n.d. (Box 130, Folder 2461)
        Includes French vaccination
        certificates for CMO and EO; French
        receipts for cinema and l'Arc de
        Triomphe; French declaration receipts
        for Saxe Commins, Richard J. Madden,
        and Eugene O'Neill, Jr.; receipt for
        The Chatterbox; train stubs, between
        Pittsburgh and New York; clipping
        regarding Strange Interlude; and
        manuscript notes.
      - Four picture frames, one in straw case, n.d. (Box 130, Folder 2462)
      - Gold rings, 1934, n.d. (Box 130, Folder 2463)
        Item A: one gold ring, engraved on
        outside in capital letters: "'Life
        Laughs with Love'"; engraved on
        inside: "January 15th 1934.
        Carlotta"; in Yamanaka & Company box.
        Item B: one gold ring, engraved on
        inside: "You are my laughter"; in
        Olga Tritt box.
      - Leather jewelry box, n.d. (Box 130, Folder 2464)
        By E. Goyard, Ainé (Paris). Has fabric cover, monogrammed "E. O'N." and yellow interior. Includes notes of explanation by CMO.
      - War ration books, one for Eugene O'Neill; one for Carlotta Monterey O'Neill, n.d. (Box 130, Folder 2465)
        Includes black case with monogram of
    - James O'Neill, Jr.
      - Black missal case stamped "James O'Neill" inside, n.d. (Box 130, Folder 2466)
        Contains: one scapular; one scapular
        fragment; one holy card; one rosary
        one photograph of a young boy; and
        one prayer card for JO, Jr.'s death.
  - OTHER
    Arranged alphabetically by title.
    - Branches and leaves, possibly from a tree at Casa Genotta (Sea Island, Ga.), in frame (Box 130, Folder 2467)
    - Dog collar for Silverdene Emblem, n.d. (Box 130, Folder 2468)
      Engraved in capital letters: "Blemie
      O'Neill, Château du Plessis, St.
      Antoine du Rocher."
    - Dramatiska teatern (Stockholm, Sweden)
      - Blue banner: "The Royal Dramatic Theatre, Stockholm"; yellow banner: Eugene O'Neill, 27. XI. 1956", 1956 Nov 27 (Box 130, Folder 2469)
      - Yellow banner: "The Royal Dramatic Theatre"; blue banner: Eugene O'Neill, 1888 16/10 1958", 1958 Oct 16 (Box 130, Folder 2470)
    - "A Map of Hudson's River Traced Northerly from Yonkers to Croton Bay," reproduction of 1926 print, n.d. (Box 130, Folder 2471)
      Inscribed by James Speyer.
- Artwork, 1922-1955; Series VII; 0.2; (1 box)
  Series VI, Artwork, is arranged alphabetically by
  artist and then by title.
  - Baldridge, Cyrus Leroy. "Eugene O'Neill," etching, 1930
  - Covarrubias, Miguel
    - [Eugene O'Neill], caricature, pen and ink drawing, [1922?] (Box 131, Folder 2472)
      Inscribed by Covarrubias to EO.
    - [Eugene O'Neill and Jimmy Durante], watercolor caricature (Box 131, Folder 2473)
      See: [Original framing material] in box 152, folder 2638a
  - Decatur, Henry R. [Architectural drawing for Eugene O'Neill's headstone], negative photostat, 1953
  - Frueh, Alfred Joseph
    - [Carlotta Monterey O'Neill], pen and ink drawing
    - "Dear Grand'ma," pen and ink and watercolor (Box 131, Folder 2474)
    - "G & A Frueh," watercolor, n.d. (Box 131, Folder 2475)
    - [Man painting three bottles while nude model reads newspaper], pen and ink and watercolor, 1955 Feb 26
    - "O'Niel & Co," pen and ink and watercolor (Box 131, Folder 2476)
    - [Valentine showing castle], pen and ink and watercolor (Box 131, Folder 2477)
      On back: "Woe is us."
    - [Valentine showing man and woman], pen and ink and watercolor (Box 131, Folder 2478)
      On back: "For my valentine."
  - Hirschfeld, Al. "Impressions of the Play of the Week," six prints, in portfolio, n.d.
    Includes: The Iceman Cometh; Henry IV (Part I); Rashomon; The Velvet Glove; The Dybbuk; and Waiting for Godot.
  - Jones, Robert Edmond
    - [Back room and section of bar in The Iceman Cometh ], pen and ink and watercolor drawing, [1946]
    - [Bar and section of the back room in The Iceman Cometh ], pen and ink and watercolor drawing, [1946]
    - [Ezra Mannon in Mourning Becomes Electra ], oil painting, n.d. (Box 131, Folder 2479)
    - [Mannon house in Mourning Becomes Electra ], watercolor drawing, n.d.
    - [Mannon house and grounds in Mourning Becomes Electra ], watercolor painting (Box 131, Folder 2480)
  - Lewis, Martin
    - "Trees at Gotemba," etching, n.d.
    - "Wind and Rain," etching
  - Quinn, Edmond Thomas. [Plaster bust of Eugene O'Neill], [192-] (Box 131, Folder 2481)
  - Rowlandson, ----. "Dr. Syntax at Covent Garden Theatre," color etching (Box 131, Folder 2482)
  - Stobbe, ----. [Portrait of Eugene O'Neill], charcoal drawing, n.d.
    Inscribed on back to CMO from
    Theodore Mann, 1964 Dec 22.
  - Sze, Mai-Mai. [Little boy carrying train of woman's dress], pen and ink drawing (Box 131, Folder 2483)
  - Toulouse-Lautrec, Henri de. [Woman with long black gloves], print, n.d.
  - Unidentified
    - [Chinese god of the theatre], wooden statue, [1928] (Box 131, Folder 2484)
    - Desire Under the Elms. Ink drawing, possibly for advertisement
    - [Headstone], pencil sketch, n.d. (Box 131, Folder 2485)
    - "James O'Neill as Virginius," three-dimensional silhouette, n.d. (Box 131, Folder 2486)
    - Long Day's Journey Into Night. Watercolor drawing of set, n.d.
    - [Man sitting near book case], etching, n.d.
      Inscribed to CMO from Karl Ragnar
      Gierow.
    - [Noh mask (straight painted hair)], paint on wood, n.d. (Box 131, Folder 2487)
    - [Noh mask (wispy painted hair)], paint on wood, n.d. (Box 131, Folder 2488)
    - [Scene in China with two men on bridge, one leading a cow], watercolor, n.d.
- Sound Recordings, 1954-1963; Series VIII; 0.4; (2 boxes)
  - Actors Theatre (New York, N.Y.). "Eugene O'Neill's Pulitzer Prize Play, Strange Interlude ," five sound discs, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in. (Columbia Masterworks), [1963] (Box 131a, Folder 2488a)
  - Robards, Jason. "Dramatic Readings from Eugene O'Neill: Long Day's Journey Into Night; A Moon for the Misbegotten; The Hairy Ape; The Iceman Cometh ," one sound disc, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in. (Columbia Masterworks), 1963 (Box 131a, Folder 2488b)
  - Canadian Broadcasting Corporation
    - " Desire Under the Elms ," seven sound discs, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in., [ca. 1954] (Box 131b, Folder 2488c)